# **ALI DEMIR**

### **Full Stack Web Developer**

Email: alidemirbay2@gmail.com Github: <a href="https://github.com/alidemirbay">https://github.com/alidemirbay</a>

Phone: 206-832-5615 Linked-In: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ali-demirbay">https://www.linkedin.com/in/ali-demirbay</a>
Bothell, WA, 98021 Portfolio: <a href="https://ad-reactportfolio.herokuapp.com/">https://ad-reactportfolio.herokuapp.com/</a>

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

Full stack web developer with a background in education. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from University of Washington. After long experience in education my new passion is web development. Proactive in learning new skills and knowledge with core competency in full-stack web development. Life-long dedication to learning and in self development. Quick-learner, organized, collaborative communicator. Look forward to bringing my skills and passion for software development to build user focused applications.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, jQuery, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Local Storage

Backend: Nodejs, Express, MERN stack, User Authentication MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose

#### PROJECTS:

Eat Da Burger: GitHub | Deployed

• Summary: An app follows MVC framework

Technologies: Node.js, Express, MySQL, Handlebars, Bootstrap

Role: Full App

## Employee Directory: GitHub | Deployed

 Summary: React app that displays a table of dynamically generated employee information and allows the user to sort and filter.

Technologies : React , Api, Bootstrap

Role: Full App

## Join Us Outside: GitHub | Deployed

Summary: MERN app that allows user organize and join outdoor events.

Technologies: React, MaterialUI, Passport.js, Cloudinary, Express, MongoDB, Node.js

Role: Backend, Database Schema, api routes, controller

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

Sub-Teacher/ Lake Washington School District

2018-2020/Redmond, WA

Covered classes in district middle and high schools.

Chemistry Teacher/Liceul Teoretic Orizont

2011-2018/Moldova

Taught chemistry, prepared students for baccalaureate axams, prepared curriculum, organized events

Chemistry Teacher, Vice-Principle/Korfez Dersaneleri

2005-2011/Turkey

• Taught chemistry, prepared students for university entrance exam, advised students to choose subject, prepared time tables, organized school-wide prep tests.

Chemistry Teacher/ Sapat International Educational Insitution

2000-2005/Kyrgyzstan

 Taught chemistry, prepared students for local and national chemistry olympiads, prepared curriculum, organized events

#### **EDUCATION:**

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development -University of Washington Seattle, WA

Master's degree, Chemistry - Dimitrie Cantemir State University Chisinau, Moldova

Bachelor's degree, Education/Chemistry- Marmara University Istanbul, Turkey